<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Best Birdies</string>

    <string name="bird1">A common and widespread albatross of the southern oceans; often seen from shore and ferries. Like other albatrosses, often scavenges at fishing boats. All plumages white-headed, often obvious at long distance (black brow only visible at close range). Adult has orange-yellow bill, brighter at the tip and thick black irregular underwing margins</string>
    <string name="bird2">The Siberian crane, also known as the Siberian white crane or the snow crane. They are distinctive among the cranes: adults are nearly all snowy white, except for their black primary feathers that are visible in flight, and with two breeding populations in the Arctic tundra of western and eastern Russia. The eastern populations migrate during winter to China, while the western population winters in Iran and India.</string>
    <string name="bird3">The Eskimo curlew was one of the most numerous shorebirds in the tundra of western Arctic Canada and Alaska. Thousands of birds were then killed per year in the late 1800s. As there has not been a reliable sighting since 1987 or a confirmed sighting since 1963, the Eskimo curlew is considered Critically Endangered or possibly extinct.The bird was about 30 cm (12 in) long and fed mostly on insects and berries.</string>
    <string name="bird4">The piping plover is a small sand-colored, sparrow-sized shorebird that nests and feeds along coastal sand and gravel beaches in North America. The adult has yellow-orange-red legs, a black band across the forehead from eye to eye, and a black stripe running along the breast line. It typically runs in short, quick spurts and then stops.</string>
    <string name="bird5"> The hyacinth macaw is a parrot native to central and eastern South America. With a length of about one meter it is longer than any other species of parrot. It is the largest macaw and the largest flying parrot species. Habitat loss and the trapping of wild birds for the pet trade have taken a heavy toll on their population in the wild, so the species is classified as Vulnerable</string>
    <string name="bird6">The California condor is a New World vulture and the largest North American land bird. It became extinct in the wild in 1987 when all remaining wild individuals were captured, but has since been reintroduced to northern Arizona and southern Utah , the coastal mountains of California, and northern Baja California in Mexico. It is the only surviving member of the genus Gymnogyps. </string>
</resources>